在我们所拥有的记忆中
There has been a war between orcs and humans
兽人与人类之间的战争已经很久了
for as long as can be remembered.
但曾经有一个时期
But there was once a time,
那时我们甚至不知道我们的敌人是谁
when we did not even know who our enemy was.
或者那邪恶的魔法对我们做过什么
Or what that evil green magic, the fel, had done to us.
但在开始的时候 我们又怎能知道
But in the beginning, how could we have known.
我们还有什么选择？
What choice did we have?
我们的世界就要消亡了
Our world was dying.
我必须为我的族人找到一个新的家
And I had to find my clan a new home.
杜隆坦
Durotan.
我能感觉到你的目光
I can feel your eyes.
我还以为你睡着了
I thought you were asleep.
我只是……
I was.
梦到穿过雪地去狩猎
Dreaming of a hunt, through the snow.
我想到一个名字
I thought of a name.
什么？ 还是你自己留着吧 媳妇
Well. Keep it to yourself, wife.
当我看到儿子的时候 我会给他选一个名字的
I'll choose a name when I meet him.
或者是闺女
Or her.
好吧
Oh.
如果我不和他一起去的话
And how will the great Durotan name his son?
伟大杜隆坦将给他儿子取个啥名？
If I do not travel with him.
儿子？
A son?
你的肚子可真能藏东西！
Can you hide your fat belly?
好过你的大脑袋里什么都没有
Better than you can hide your fat head.
这么多的部族聚集在一个地方 奥格瑞姆
So many clans from one place, Orgrim.
超颅氏族（不知道是哪个部落 随意写了个） 黑石氏族
Laughing skull. Black rock.
所有部落都在这儿了
All have been summoned.
这将是一个强大的战团
It will be a mighty warband.
我只是想知道谁会留下来打仗？
I just wonder who's left to fight?
Lok'tar ogar!胜利或死亡！
Lok'tar ogar! (Victory or death!)
胜利或死亡！
Victory or death!
黑石氏族的 去那边
Black rock, over there.
还要多久 黑手？
How much longer, Blackhand?
我们准备好了 古尔丹
We are ready, Gul'dan.
帮助我
Help me.
我的孩子 请让他走
My child. Please let him go.
我求求你了
I beg you.
她说什么？
What did she say?
她乞求你放了她的孩子
She begs for you to free her child.
但我需要他 我需要所有的人
But I need him. I need all of them.
快走！半兽人（按道理是半兽德莱尼）
Move, half breed.
- 那是什么？ - 古尔丹的魔法
- What is that? - Gul'dan's magic.
我的魔法的燃料就是生命
The fuel of my magic is life.
我们现在只有足够把我们最强的战士送过去的囚犯
We only have enough prisoners to send through our strongest warriors.
但是 这还远远不够 敌人是很脆弱的
But that will be enough. The enemy is weak.
当我们到了那边  我们会把他们作为燃料
When we arrive, we will take them as fuel.
我们将建立一个新的传送门（呵呵 黑暗之门） 而当它建成的时候
We will build a new portal. And when it is complete,
我们将把部落的所有人 全部带过去......
we will bring through all... of the Horde.
让我先走
Let me go first.
为了部落！
For the Horde!
怀了孩子？
With child?
你竟敢把这个负担 带入我的军队！
You dare bring that burden into my war band!
让我走 黑手 德拉卡！
Let me go, Blackhand. Draka!
用力 小东西 用力
Push, little one. Push.
我的儿子
My son.
为部落的新战士！
A new warrior for the Horde.
魔兽世界
WARCRAFT
铁炉堡
IRONGORGE
洛萨 过来 我有东西给你
Lothar, come. I have got something for you.
- 这是什么？ - 一个机械史上的奇迹
- What is it? - A mechanical marvel.
这是一个火枪
It's a boomstick.
怪了
Odd.
去喝点水
Take water.
你也许该想回家了 大个子
You might want to head home, big man.
有人袭击了你的一支驻军
Someone has attacked one of your garrisons.
看起来你的国王需要你 指挥官
It seems your king needs you, commander.
暴风城
Stormwind
整个军队都死完了 没有人见过任何东西
The entire garrison, and no one saw anything.
我们确实找到了一个人
We did find someone.
他在这里搜查尸体  在军营里
He was searching the bodies, here, in the barracks.
在军营？
In the barracks?
总算来了 你就是指挥官？
Finally. Are you in command?
.
这是肯瑞托的印记
That's the mark of the Kirin Tor.
你在我的城市做什么？ 玩魔法的
What are you doing in my city, spell chucker?
让我完成大厅那边的尸体的检测
Let me complete my examination of the body across the hall.
现在 我为什么要这么做？
Now why would I do that?
在那具尸体里面隐藏着这次袭击的秘密
Within that body is the secret to your attacks.
那是什么？
What was that?
你必须召唤守护者
You must summon the Guardian.
麦迪文？
Medivh?
这应该是他来解释的
It should be he who explains it.
只有国王召才能唤守护者
Only the king summons the Guardian.
带他去闪金镇
Get him to Goldshire.
- 什么样的野兽？ - 都是谣言 陛下
- What kind of beasts? - Rumors, your Majesty.
让30个人驻军悄无声息的消失是怎么做到的
How does a garrison of 30 men disappear without a whisper.
恶魔（目测指的是燃烧军团的绿色能量）
The fel.
或者至少在它的影响下
Or at least it's influence.
就是他吗？
Is this him?
陛下
Your Majesty.
爸爸
Dad.
谢谢你 儿子
Thank you, son.
所以 你是谁 法师？
So who are you, mage?
我的名字是卡德加 一个见习守护者
My name is Khadgar. I'm a Guardian novitiate.
曾经是 但我放弃了我的誓言
I was. I renounced my vows.
你的意思是你是一个逃犯？
You mean you're a fugitive?
我并没有躲
I'm not hiding.
陛下
Your Majesty.
我可能已经放弃了我的训练 但 我没有放弃我的能力
I may have left my training but I didn't leave my abilities behind.
我感觉到一些东西
I senses something.
黑暗的东西 当它强大的时候 简直有味道散发出来
Dark forces, when it's strong it... almost has a smell.
我发现如此邪恶东西是如此接近 以至于我无法忽略它
Knowing that something so evil was so close I couldn't just ignore it.
这是怎么回事？
What's going on out there?
是狼烟 长官 东南方向
Smoke, Sir. The southeast.
陛下 我请求你赶紧让通知守护者
Your Majesty, I urge you to engage the Guardian with all haste.
- 他们已经到艾尔文森林了 - 夜色镇已经烧起来了
- They've reached Elwynn Forest. - The Grand Hamlet is burning.
是袭击？
An attack?
- 什么？ - 不要给卡伦说话了
- What? - Stop requesting Callan.
不要管我们之间的事
Stay out of my business.
他想追随父亲的脚步
He wants to follow in his father's footsteps.
我的儿子并不需要你的帮助
My son doesn't need your help.
跟你的王后说话的时候情谨慎点
Tread carefully when you talk to your queen.
你首先应该是我的妹妹
You are my sister first.
你最后一次去卡拉赞是什么时候？
When was your last visit to Karazhan?
和你一起吗？ 我不知道... 6年了吧？
With you. I don't know... 6 years?
然后你从此之后就和麦迪文没有联系了？
And you had no contact with Medivh since?
反正不是因为没有尝试过联系
Not for the lack of trying.
好吧
Well.
他现在不能躲我们了
He can't hide from us now.
召唤守护者
The Guardian is summoned.
上来
Get on.
祝你好运
Good luck.
好
Okay.
出发吧！
Let me go!
霜狼氏族不加入追捕？
Frostwolves do not join the hunt?
我们更喜欢我们的敌人是全副武装的  拿着斧头的 而不是孩子
We prefer our enemies armed with an axe, not a child.
我们现在是被指挥者 杜隆坦 尊重传统
We have been commanded, Durotan. Respect the old ways.
在这些麦堆里的某些地方一定有值得尊重的敌人
There must be a worthy foe somewhere on this dung heap.
把他们都找出来
Find them all!
尽量不要杀太多  我们需要他们活着
Try not to kill too many, we need them alive.
洛萨
Lothar.
莫罗斯
Moroes.
看看你 你一点都没老
Look at you. You haven't aged a bit.
其他人呢？
Where is everyone?
很多事情都改变了
Many things have changed.
能量必须锁在这儿 还有知识
The power that must be locked away here, the knowledge.
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
我甚至不知道有这么多书存在
I didn't know so many books even existed.
在这里等一下
Wait here.
尽量不要碰任何东西
And try not to touch anything.
- 他谁也不见? - 世界一直很和平
- He sees no one? - The world's been at peace.
很高兴你来这儿 洛萨
Good you are here, Lothar.
比起我这个老人 守护者看到你这张熟悉的面孔
It would do the Guardian a world of good
会觉得世界更美好的
to see a friendly face beyond this old one.
他无法拒绝你 和乌瑞恩国王
He can't refuse you... nor King Wrynn.
不 除非他被召唤
Not if he's summoned.
歇歇
Chop chop.
你叫他来的吗 莫罗斯？
Did you summon him, Moroes?
不是 他没有
No. He did not.
所以 你成了一名雕塑家？
So. You become a sculptor?
我正在做一个傀儡
I'm making a golem.
它通常需要几年的魔法来渗入粘土 但在这里它……
It usually takes years of magic to sip into the clay, but up here it's...
...要快得多
much faster.
给莫罗斯的团队找点人 帮助打扫周围的房子
Makes someone to keep Moroes company. Help to clean up around the house.
谢谢
Thank you.
很高兴见到你 洛萨
It's good to see you, Lothar.
我们需要你的指引 麦迪文
We need your guidance, Medivh.
我们的国王召唤你
Our king summons you.
在楼下的男孩是谁？
Who's the boy downstairs?
喂？
Hello?
守护者？
Guardian?
好好看看周围？
Have a good look around?
想想如果一旦这些都是你的你将做什么？
Getting some ideas what you are going to do with the place once it's yours?
守护者 我已经放弃了我的誓言
Guardian, I've renounced my vow.
我并不想来这儿 我发誓 守护者
I didn't want to come here. I swear, Guardian.
我敦促他们找到你 我告诉他们...
I urged them to find you. I told them...
...你才是解释这些的人
you should be the one to explain.
解释什么？
Explain what?
恶魔能量!
Fel!
在艾泽拉斯？
In Azeroth?
在军营 其中的一具尸体
In the barracks, one of the bodies.
守护者 什么是恶魔能量？
Guardian, what is the fel?
不同于其他任何一个法术 它滋生于生命本身
A magic unlike any other. It feeds on life itself.
它污染它的使用者  转换它所碰到的所有东西
It pollutes the user, twisting everything it touches.
它给予强大的能量 但需要付出惨痛的代价
It promises great power but it exacts a terrible price.
在艾泽拉斯没有恶魔能量存在的地方
There is no place for the fel in Azeroth.
你做了正确的事情
You've done the right thing.
我们一起去
We'll go.
嘿 你回家吧
Hey. Go home, you.
站进来
Step in.
- 麦迪文 - 陛下
- Medivh. - Your Grace.
太久没见你了
It has been too long.
来吧
Come.
帮助我们找到这些麻烦的根源
Help us get to the roots of these troubles about.
- 什么样的野兽？ - 他们说是巨人
- What kind of beasts? - They are saying giants.
全副武装的巨人 骑着狼来的
Armed giants. Wolves to carry them.
巨大的势不可挡的怪物
Huge unstoppable monsters
其他王国呢？ 他们是否遇到同样的遭遇？
What are the other kingdoms? Are they suffering the same?
都来寻求我们的保护 但不够相信我们 没有告诉我们什么
All seek our protection yet not trust us enough to tell us anything.
我们对这些所谓的怪物一无所知
We know nothing about these so call monsters.
我们需要俘虏
We need prisoners.
即使是一具尸体 也能告诉我们一些东西
Even a corpse can tell us something.
我不知道我们处于什么样的危险之中 麦迪文
I don't know what danger we're in, Medivh.
我的存在就是为了防止这种状况 陛下
I exist to protect this realm, my lord.
这就是我找你来的目的
It is my very purpose.
我是守护者
I am the Guardian.
至少暂时还是
At least for the time being anyhow.
是的
Yes.
我们该怎么办？ 他叫什么名字？
What are we going to do about... What is his name?
卡德加 陛下
Khadgar, sire.
他会和我们一起去
He'll be coming with us.
那好吧
Well then.
我们最好马上出发
We better get going.
艾尔文森林
ELWYNN FOREST
停下！
Halt!
怎么可能
It can't be.
- 这是什么？ - 看不出来什么
- What is this? - Can't tell from the look of it.
.
守护者
Guardian.
队伍靠拢！
Close ranks!
小心背后！
Watch your back!
胜利或死亡！
Victory or death!
小心左侧翼！
Watch the flank to your left!
注意你的侧翼！
Watch your flank!
- 注意你的侧翼！ - 在你的左边！
- Watch your flank! - To your left!
守护者！
Guardian!
现在你死了 你这畜生！
Now you die, you beast!
不要尝试和他们拼蛮力
Don't try and take them on with brute force.
他们更强壮 放聪明点
They are stronger. Be smarter.
恶魔能量
The fel.
他们都死了
They're all dying.
只有绿色的！
Only the green ones!
杀死那个大混蛋！
Kill that big bastard!
杜隆坦 快跑
Durotan. Move.
守护者 守护者 你做了什么？
Guardian. Guardian, what did you do?
我是对的 不是吗？ 是这里
I was right, wasn't I? It's here.
- 你要去哪里？ - 把这些人安全带回暴风城
- Where are you going? - Get these men safely back to Stormwind.
我必须回到卡拉赞
I've to return to Karazhan.
你今天做的很好
You did well today.
- 守护者呢？ - 卡拉赞
- Where's the Guardian? - Karazhan.
我们需要俘虏 你的马呢？
We need a prisoner. Where's your horse?
- 呃他们把我的马骑走了 - 真的吗？
- Uh. They took my horse. - Really?
待在那儿别动
Just stay there.
你有多爱你的主人？
How much do you love your master?
我会做到的
I'll do it.
滚开！
Back off!
可惜了 可以做个好外套的
Pity. It would have make a good coat.
在这里！
Over here!
- 你一个人搞定的？ - 是的
- You took it alone. - Yes.
看起来是个小点的混蛋
Looks like the runt to the litter.
你 你是什么？
You. What are you?
你们为什么 袭击我们的领地？
And why do you attack our lands?
- 他不知道你说什么 - 你说我们的语言？
- He does not know what you speak. - You speak our language?
你再用他们的语言说一句
Speak one more word in their language.
我会弄穿你的舌头
And I will wear your tongue.
我不会再警告你第二次
I will not warn you again.
- 叫他停下来 - 你自己说
- Tell him to stop. - You tell him.
不用谢
You're welcome.
你有名字吗？
Have you a name?
你理解我们的语言
You understand our language.
你有名字吗？
Again, have you a name?
迦罗娜
Garona.
她自称迦罗娜
She calls herself, Garona.
你是什么样的存在？
What kind of being are you?
她似乎更像我们 比起......和我们战斗的那些野兽来看
She seems more like us than those... beast we fought.
兽人
Orc.
兽人？
Orc?
那是你是什么？ 宠物兽人？
That's what you are? Or the beast in the cage was?
我知道在七大王国的每场比赛 我从来没有听说过兽人
I know every races in the Seven Kingdoms. I've never heard of orc.
告诉我你来自哪里
Show me where you come from.
这不是兽人的世界
This is not orc world.
兽人的世界已经灭亡了
Orc world is dead.
兽人现在要占领这个世界
Orcs take this world now.
不是来自这个世界
Not from this world.
那你怎么来的？
How did you get here?
黑暗之门
The great gate.
深入地面 通过魔法把我们带到这里
Deep in ground and through magic brought us here.
但你是怎么学习我们的语言？
But how did you learn our language?
兽人为了黑暗之门抓的俘虏
Orc take prisoner for the gate.
- 我向他们学习 - 俘虏？
- I learn from them. - Prisoners?
我们的人呢？ 他们是否还活着吗？
Our people? Are they alive?
是的
Yes.
- 许多 - 为什么？
- Many. - Why?
为了给黑暗之门提供养料
To feed the gate.
为了把部落带过来占领你们的世界
To bring the Horde to take your world.
你带我们找到他们
You'll take us to them.
不
No.
你会带我们到他们 否则你的下场 会跟你笼子里的朋友一样
You'll take us to them or you will end up like your friend in the cage.
你以为你很可怕吗
You think you are fearsome.
兽人孩子的宠物都比你更可怕
Orc children have pets more fearsome than you.
我们并不想成为恐怖的东西 迦罗娜
We're not trying to be fearsome, Garona.
我们只是试图保护我们的人民 我们的家庭
We are trying to protect our people, our families.
如果你帮助我们 我会给你我的誓言
If you help us. I give you my oath.
你将拥有自由
You will have your freedom.
无畏的黑手
Fearsome Blackhand.
部落的酋长
Warchief of the Horde.
您让小个子们杀死了你的战士
You have allowed the smallteeths to kill your warriors.
更糟糕的是
Worse.
你的逃跑让你的子民蒙羞
You shamed your people by running from an enemy.
你已经软弱到不能说话了吗 毁灭者？
Are you too weak to talk, destroyer?
部落不留弱者
The Horde has no use for weakness.
尊重我们的传统 酋长
Respect our tradition, warchief.
你知道惩罚是什么
You know the penalty.
死亡
Death.
开始吧
Done.
- 你敢打断这个审判？ - 我们尽力战斗了！
- You dare interrupt this judgment? - We fought hard!
他们的法师使用您的魔法对抗我们
Their warlock use your fel against us.
只有我可以控制恶魔能量！
Only I can control the fel!
我看到你和你的人活了下来
I see you and your men have survived.
也许黑手让你从战场安全离开
Perhaps Blackhand kept you safely away from the battlefield.
也许他知道你们也是软弱的
Maybe he knows you are weak too.
你在挑衅我  小酋长
Do you wish to challenge me, little chieftain.
我并不是怀疑你 古尔丹
I do not question, Gul'dan.
但恶魔能量生于死亡 必将有代价
But the fel is born of death, must have a price.
用生命付出的代价
A price paid in lives taken.
你要不要抱抱你的儿子？
Will you hold your son?
他会成为一个伟大的酋长
He will be a great chieftain.
像他的父亲一样 一个天生的领袖
Like his father, a born leader.
我现在不是领袖了
I was no leader today.
他已经在向您挑战了
He challenges you already.
如果古尔丹可以感染像他一样的无辜新生儿
If Gul'dan can infect born as innocent as he.
我们其余的人还有什么机会？
What chance do the rest of us have?
不管发生什么
Whatever happens.
我看到你了
I see you.
这个门 谁告诉古尔丹的？
This gate, who showed it to Gul'dan?
谁引导他来艾泽拉斯的？
Who lead him to Azeroth?
古尔丹称他为恶魔
Gul'dan call him a demon.
你看到了吗？
Did you see it?
没有看到脸  但听到过声音...
Not the face, but the voice...
像火与灰烬一般
Like fire and ash.
我会在这里 如果你需要我
I'll be here if you need me.
你的伴侣？
Your mate.
我可以在他到我面前之前杀了你
I could kill you before he even reaches me.
洛萨？
Lothar?
他是我弟弟
He is my brother.
国王才是我的伴侣
The king is my mate.
你是酋长夫人？
You are the chieftain's wife then?
应该是
I suppose so.
这样的话杀了你会带给我带来更大的荣誉
Then killing you will bring me even greater honor.
在我们这儿不一样
Not among my kind.
这是一个寒冷的夜晚
It is a cold night.
我想你可能会用上这些
I thought you might use these.
它会让你觉得暖和
It will warm you.
今晚更多我们的村庄被烧毁
More of our villages burned tonight.
其中之一是我出生的村庄
One of them is the village of my birth.
我无法想象你经历过什么样的恐怖 迦罗娜
I can not imagine what horrors you have been through, Garona.
但这些并不需要发生
But this does not need to happen.
我们在这片土地上和平生活许多年了
We have peace in these lands for many years now.
来自世界各地种族之间和平相处
Peace between races from all over the world.
这是什么？
What is this?
我可以把它解开
I can have it removed.
你可以在这里生活 迦罗娜
There is a life here for you, Garona.
和我们一起 自由的生活
With us. A life of freedom.
如果你想要的话
If you want it.
黑暗之门
The great gate.
光明源于黑暗 黑暗涌现光明
From light comes darkness and from darkness, light.
擦 说的真清楚
Well, that's clear.
问阿洛迪
Ask Alodi.
阿洛迪
Alodi.
啊 再次见到树木真是开心
Ahh. It's good to see trees again.
还有雪
And the snow.
即使从远处看
Even from a distance.
还记得我们穿越霜风峭壁（国服对Forstwind的翻译）的丘陵追踪血牛吗？
Remember when we would track blood ox through the Frostwind dunes?
总会有肉吃的 生活总会继续
There was always meat. Always life.
你明白的 这很奇怪
You don't think it's strange
当古尔丹上台时我们失去了我们的家
that we lost our home when Gul'dan came to power.
一个兽人毁灭不了一个世界 杜隆坦
One orc could not kill a world, Durotan.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
看看你的周围 难道没有让你想起什么？
Look around you. Does it not remind you of something?
古尔丹在哪儿施展他的魔法 哪里的土地便死亡了
Wherever Gul'dan works his magic, the land dies.
如果我们的人民要在这里安家 我的朋友
If our people are to make a home here, my friend.
古尔丹必须被阻止
Gul'dan must be stopped.
我们不够强大 不足以击败古尔丹
We are not powerful enough to defeat Gul'dan.
当然
No.
当然不够
但如果有人类的帮助 我们 可以做到
But with the humans help, we could be.
我想要那个武器
I want that weapon.
你有我保护你
You'll have me to protect you.
我不需要任何人来保护我
I need no one to protect me.
你在看什么？
What are you looking at?
书呆子 你第一个守夜
Bookworm. Take the first watch.
尊敬的指挥官  我的名字是卡德加
Respectfully, Commander, my name is Khadgar.
致以我最深的歉意 卡德加
My deepest apologies, Khadgar.
你看 我认为我们是友好的
You see, I thought we bonded when
我没有在你闯入皇家兵营的时候把你扔进牢房里
I didn't put you in a prison cell for breaking into royal barracks.
现在开始守夜吧
Now take the watch.
好吧 至少你没在看书
Well. At least you're not reading.
他想和我睡
He wishes to lie with me.
请你再说一遍？
I beg your pardon?
你会受伤的
You will be injured
- 我不想和你睡 - 好吧
- I don't want to lie with you. - Good.
你不会是个好的的伴侣
You would not be an effective mate.
你笑什么？
Why do you laugh?
我不知道你们人类做这样的事怎么活下来的
I can't see how you humans survive such a thing.
没有肌肉来保护你们 脆弱的骨头会断裂的
No muscles to protect you. Brittle bones that break.
你看起来与我们没那么大差别的嘛
You don't look that different to us.
那你又是怎么活下来的？
How did you survive?
断骨愈合后会更强
Broken bones heal stronger.
我的就非常强
Mine are very strong.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
没什么
Do not be.
我的名字 迦罗娜
My name, Garona,
这在兽人的语言中意味着“诅咒”
it means "cursed" in orc.
我母亲因为生下了我而被活活烧死
My mother was burned alive for giving birth to me.
他们还是让你活下来了
They kept you alive though.
古尔丹让我活下来的
Gul'dan did.
他给了我她的牙 为了记住她
He gave me her tusk to remember her.
我的父母在我6岁的时候把我给了肯瑞托
My parents gave me to the Kirin Tor when I was 6 years old.
这是我最后一次见到他们还有... 我的所有兄弟姐妹
That's the last time I saw them or... any of my brothers and sisters.
把孩子献给肯瑞托 能够给家庭带来荣耀
It brings a family honor to offer a child to the Kirin Tor.
将他们的儿子送往达拉然空中之城
To have their son taken up to the floating city of Dalaran
得到这片大陆上最强大的法师的培训
and be trained by the most powerful mages in the land.
但如果他逃跑了 可就不是那么回事了
Less so, to have them run away.
好吧 那还比较嗨皮
Well. That was cheerful.
黑暗之门
The great gate.
为什么他们需要这么多俘虏？
Why do they need so many prisoners?
像木材用来生火一样
Like wood for a fire.
绿色魔法需要生命来打开传送门
Green magic takes life to open the gate.
他们打算还要带多少兽人过来？
How many more orcs are they planning on bringing?
所有的 这里只是一个战团
All of them. This is just a warband.
当门打开时 古尔丹会将整个部落带过来
When the portal is open, Gul'dan will bring the Horde.
让他们回到暴风城
Get them back to Stormwind.
我们先走
We ride ahead.
迦罗娜 我们该走了 这里不安全...
Garona, we should go. It's not safe...
杜隆坦
Durotan.
在北部 有一块黑色的岩石 高及苍穹
To the north, there is a black rock that touches the sky.
我将与他们的领袖会面
I would meet with their leader.
你要挑战他？
To challenge him?
我看见你带这些小个子到我们的营地
I saw you, lead the smallteeths to our encampment.
他们已经看到这里正在修建什么了
They have seen what is being built.
只有你知道 古尔丹计划在我的子民身上做什么
And only you know, what Gul'dan has planned for my people.
他的法术对所有东西来说都是死亡
His magic is death to all things.
我们必须阻止他
He must be stopped.
告诉他 在黑色岩石那儿 当太阳升到最高的时候
Tell him, the black rock, when the sun is highest.
我会的
I will.
酋长
Chieftain.
如果我回来 你会让我加入你的部落吗？
If I returned, would you take me into your clan?
你在这儿跟他们在一起更安全
You're safer here, with them.
正如你所担心的吗？
Is it as you feared?
- 恶魔能量无处不在 - 那你一定不能再离开
- The fel is everywhere. - Then you mustn't leave again.
他们现在比以往任何时候都更需要守护者的帮助
They need the Guardian's help now more than ever.
也许那个小男孩可以提供帮助
Maybe the boy can help.
- We need solution!
- Easy for you to say!
- 矮人锻造师们必须加班 - 你对我们还不如狗
- The Dwarf enforgers must work overtime. - You treat us no better than dogs.
- 我们不会给你们提供更多了！ - 够了！
- We shall supply you no more! - Enough!
你们过去无论是对部队还是仲裁都来暴风城寻求帮助
You have all called on Stormwind in the past either for troops or arbitration.
如果我们不团结起来对抗敌人 我们将灭亡
If we do not unite to fight this enemy, we will perish.
暴风城需要战士 武器 马……
Stormwind needs soldiers, arms, horses...
哈！我们还要照顾自己的王国
Ha! We have our own kingdoms to look after.
- 打你自己的仗去吧！ - 陛下
- Fight your own wars! - Your Majesty.
指挥官
Commander.
兽人正在建设一个传送门 他们计划通过它带来一支军队
The Orcs are building a portal, through which they plan to bring an army.
如果我们现在不阻止他们 我们可能再也没有下一次机会了
If we do not stop them now, we may never get another opportunity.
他在哪里？ 艾泽拉斯的守护者在哪儿？
Where is he? Where is the protector of Azeroth?
守护者在哪儿？
Where the Guardian?
麦迪文在哪儿？
Where is Medivh?
- 我的君主 - 我建议我们暂时休会
- My liege. - I suggest we take a recess.
随你们休多久 我们结束了
Take as long as you like. We're done.
指挥官
Commander.
第四纵队已经退回暴风城了
What's left of the 4th has retreated from Stonewatch.
哪些人还活着？
What's left?
卡伦是伤者之一
Callan is among the injured.
爸爸？
Dad?
我很好 没事
I'm fine. It's fine.
我很担心你
You had me worried.
你队伍中的其他人呢？
Where's the rest of your troop?
他们把其中大多数还活着的带走了
They took most of them alive.
我们将把他们带回来
We'll get them back.
不要这么着急
Don't be in such a hurry.
你是我拥有的一切
You're all I have.
我知道 但我是一名军人
I know. I'm a soldier.
如果他认为他可以击败单独古尔丹 他也不会要求本次会面
He would not ask for this meeting if he thought he could defeat Gul'dan alone.
- 恶魔能量一定是真让他感到害怕了 - 杜隆坦无所畏惧
- The fel must truly terrified him. - Durotan is scared of nothing.
地点
The location.
本次会议太突然了
The suddenness of this meeting.
- 听起来像一个陷阱 - 不是这样的
- Sounds like a trap. - It is not.
- 可能是这样 - 不是这样
- Could be. - It is not.
- 可能是 - 不是这样
你在想什么？
What do you think?
这是不能忽略的太好机会
It's too good an opportunity to ignore.
我认为我们别无选择
I think we have no choice.
我们必须阻止兽人从打开传送门
We must stop the orcs from opening the portal.
但我们需要帮助
But we will need help.
- 如果他是在说谎呢？ - 兽人不会说谎
- And if he's lying? - Orcs do not lie.
- 如果他是呢？ - 那就没有荣誉可言了
- What if he is? - There is no honor in it.
那他出卖自己的族人 又何来荣誉呢？
And where's the 'honor' in him betraying his own people?
杜隆坦是在保护他的氏族他的敌人是恶魔能量
Durotan is protecting his clan. His enemy is the fel.
古尔丹才是背叛者
Gul'dan is the betrayer.
这个兽人 杜隆坦 你对他有什么了解吗？
This orc, Durotan. How do you know him?
他释放了我 他深受族人喜爱
He freed me, and he is loved by his clan.
他是一个强大的酋长
He's a strong chieftain.
强大的首领必须赢得他们的宗族信任
Strong chiefs must earn their clans trust.
如果我们期待你加入我们的行列
If we are to expect you to join us.
我们必须赢得你的信任
We must earn yours.
保护好自己
To defend yourself.
用这玩意儿？
With this?
是的
Yes.
找到守护者
Find the Guardian.
这是什么？
What is this?
守护者？
Guardian?
呃
Uh.
传送门 我们在泥沼看到它了
The gate. We saw it, in the morass.
我正把我能发现的所有的线索全部放到一起
I've been putting together all the clues I can about it.
这个 这幅画
This. This drawing.
- 你从哪里抄的？ - 守护者
- Where did you copy it from? - Guardian.
这个呢？
And this?
这个呢？ 这个呢？
And this? And this?
我一直在不断研究 从我察觉到恶魔能量的存在开始
I've been researching ever since I felt the presence of the fel.
我才是守护者 我 而不是你
I am the Guardian. Me, not you.
至少现在还不是
Not yet.
我只是想你可能会需要一些帮助
I just thought you might appreciate some help.
不要妄想能帮助我
Don't presume you can help me.
你对我所对抗的力量一无所知
You have no idea the forces I contend with.
如果你想帮助保护国王
If you want to help, protect the king.
就将恶魔能量的事留给我
You leave the fel to me.
- 有趣的选择 - 守护者
- Interesting choice. - Guardian.
收拾行囊去西大门
Pack up and move to the west gate.
你留在这儿
You there.
收拾你的摊子赶紧出发！
Pack up your stall and get moving now!
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
- 我发现了一本书 - 然后呢
- I found a book. - Of course you did.
有一个插图讲述了传送门
There was an illustration that showed the gate
就像我们看到正在修建的这个一样
like the one we saw being built.
- 对不起抱歉 - 卡德加
- Sorry. Sorry. - Khadgar.
听着 我试图向守护者展示但他怒不可遏
Listen. I tried to show the Guardian but he became furious.
他烧毁了我所有的研究
He burned all my research.
如果我没有把这个藏在我的长袍里 他也会把这个烧了的
He would have burn this too If I hadn't hidden it in my robe.
不是这样 翻一下 看这里
No, turn the page. Here.
看吧
Look.
看到了吗？
See.
你觉得这张图意味着什么？
What do you think the image means?
兽人是被召唤过来的
The orcs were summoned.
从门的这一边 他们是被邀请过来的
From this side of the gate. They were invited in.
守护者 烧毁了你的研究
And the Guardian burned your research.
他可能只是想保护你
He's probably just trying to protect you.
赶紧走吧
Now go away.
找个埋伏的好地方
Good spot for an ambush.
我们的哨兵都处于有利位置
Our sentries are well placed.
我会再次检查的
I will check again.
你要求和人类的领导者面谈
You asked to speak with the humanking.
就是他
Here he stands.
我是莱恩国王
I am the King Llane.
我听说你想谈判
I'm told you wished to talk.
问他是否有计划回到自己的家？
Ask him if they plan to return to their home?
我们的世界被破坏了
Our world is destroyed.
没有什么可以回去的了
There is nothing to go back to.
我们对你们世界的毁灭没有任何责任
We are not responsible for destroying your world.
和我们开战解决不了任何问题
War with us will solve nothing.
他说  “兽人 战争解决一切”
He says, "Orcs, war solves everything."
那他来这里干嘛？
Then why is he here?
为了拯救我的人民
To save my people.
恶魔能量不只带走受害者的生命
Fel takes life from more than it's victims.
还会杀死土地和使用它们的人
Kills the earth and corrupts those who use it.
古尔丹会用他的死亡魔法毒害所有东西
Gul'dan will poison everything with his death magic.
如果我的族人要生存下去 古尔丹必须被消灭
If my people are to survive, Gul'dan must be destroyed.
在两天之内 我们抓的人类...
In 2 suns, the humans we have captured...
...将被用做大门的献祭
be used to fuel the portal.
如果你攻击我们的营地 并引走他们的战士
If you attack our camp, and draw his warriors away,
霜狼氏族  会杀了他
Frostwolf clan, will kill him.
两天
Two days.
如果我们这样做 在那之前你要保护好我的子民
If we do this, you will protect my people until then.
我会尽力的
I will try.
这是一个陷阱！
It's a trap!
背叛者死！
Traitor die!
撤退！
Retreat!
撤退！ 撤退到我们的营地！
Back! Return to our camp!
速度撤退！
Fall back!
保持一起！
Stay together!
集中精力 像以前一样
Focus. Like old times.
挡住你的侧翼！
Cover your flank!
Spread out!
推！
Swords!
你还好吗？
You alright?
快走 你死了对我们没好处
You are no good to us dead. Go.
那我去杀其他的
I'll get the others.
速度撤退！
Fall back!
我们都会出去的
We're all getting out.
麦迪文将隔开我们的后方
Medivh will cover our retreat.
Fall back!
迦罗娜！
Garona!
保持一起！
Stay together!
速度撤退！
Fall back!
继续努力吧！
Go on, now!
血脉守护者在哪儿？
Where's the bloody Guardian?
保护国王 我得到了他们
Protect the king. I got them.
往后撤！
Move back!
盾阵！
Shield FORMATION!
退到高地
Retreat to the plateau.
速度撤退！
Fall back!
上山 快！
Up the hill. Move!
麦迪文
Medivh.
麦迪文 快停下！
Medivh, take it down!
麦迪文！
Medivh!
坚持住 儿子
Hold on, son.
爸爸
Dad.
为了艾泽拉斯
For Azeroth.
麦迪文！
Medivh!
停
Stop.
No.
卡伦
Callan.
他在这里！
He's here!
他到底怎么了？
What's wrong with him?
我们要带他回卡拉赞
We need to get him to Karazhan.
- 我去找匹马 - 你不用在路上耗时间
- I'll get the horses. - You won't make any time by road.
就用我的狮鹫吧
Take one of my birds.
将他放进泉水里
Place him in the font.
- 莫罗斯 他出什么问题了 - 我告诉他不要离开卡拉赞
- Moroes, what's wrong with him - I told him not to leave Karazhan.
我得走了
I have to go.
我们需要肯瑞托的帮助 现在
We need the help of the Karin Tor, now.
去吧
Go.
这里有药 我必须准备一下 你先和他待一会儿
There are medicines I must prepare. Sit with him.
你和孩子必须马上离开
You and the baby must leave now.
你就是个叛徒 杜隆坦
You're a traitor, Durotan.
不
No.
不要忘了我们曾今是什么样子的 你曾今是什么样子
One who values what we once were. Like you used to.
那个时代已经过去了
That time is past.
我们现在不过是恶魔能量的燃料罢了
We are but fuel for the fel now.
还是有希望的 黑手
There is still hope, Blackhand.
我们的子孙后代
Our children.
不要让我带走更多无辜者的生命 年轻的酋长
Do not make me take more innocent lives, young chieftain.
如果我投降呢...
If I submit...
...你会让我的人活下来吗？
will you let my people be?
我们的孩子叫什么？
What will I call our son?
古伊尔
Go'el
是你
You.
老男人去哪儿了？
Where's the older man?
他让我照顾你
He told me to watch you.
- 国王呢 - 他还活着
- The king. - He is alive.
洛萨的儿子死了
Lothar's son is dead.
是我要求这次会面
I argued for the meeting.
洛萨会恨我的
Lothar will hate me.
这取决于你
This upsets you.
他是一个伟大的战士
He is a great warrior.
他保卫好他的人民
He defends his people well.
对兽人来说是个不错的伴侣
A good mate for an orc.
我不是兽人
I am no orc.
我也不是人类
I am no human either.
年轻的时候 我能感到自己与同类的格格不入
When I was younger, I used to feel apart from my kin.
我远行至各地 寻求智慧
I traveled far and wide, looking for... wisdom.
试着感受与所有灵魂的联系——我被赋予了守护它们的职责
Feel a connection with all the souls I was charged with protecting.
在我的旅行途中 我遇到了一个强大而高尚的种族
On my travel, I met a strong and noble people.
其中 一位女士接纳了我本来的样子
Among them, a female, who accepted me for what I was.
她是爱我的
Who loved me.
但这不是我注定拥有的生活
It was not a life I was fated to have,
但它教会了我一些东西
but it taught me something.
如果爱情是你想要的
If love is what you need,
你就必须愿意走遍天涯海角去追寻
you must be willing to travel to the end the world to find it.
你离开了你的伴侣
You left your mate.
去找洛萨吧
Go find Lothar.
进圈子里来
Step inside the circle.
这...是我送给你的礼物  迦罗娜
This... is my gift to you, Garona.
一整个世界  换来一尊雕像
A whole world and exchange for a statue.
神真是奇怪的生物
Gods are strange creatures.
霜狼 你是一个务实的人
Frostwolves, you are a practical people.
我们这些从南方来的总是羡慕你们这些
Those of us from the south have always admired that about you.
当大门打开 当部落的其他人加入我们的时候
When the portal opens, when the rest of the Horde join us
我们会给他们恶魔能量
we will give them the fel.
- 所有人 - 杜隆坦不会同意的！
- All of them. - Durotan did not agree to this!
为什么你会在乎一个叛徒怎么想？
And why would you care what that traitor thinks?
是时候给霜狼氏族找个新的领袖了
It is time for a new leader of the Frostwolf clan.
一个从心里明白他的部落最大利益是什么的人
One who has the best interest of his orcs in mind.
一个明白古尔丹的远见的人
One who appreciates Gul'dan's vision,
...他的权力
his power.
来吧
Come.
我将赐予你恶魔能量
I will grant you the fel.
杜隆坦 他……已经警告过霜狼氏族对抗恶魔能量了
Durotan, he... has poisoned the Frostwolves against the fel.
让我把他们集合过来  把他们带来这里
Let me gather them, bring them here.
在他们面前赐予我恶魔能量  让他们看到...
Grant me the fel in front of them, let them see...
我将变得多么的强壮
How much stronger I become.
正如我所说  一个务实的人
As I said, a practical people.
这是新的曙光
This is a new dawn.
部落的时代
The time of the Horde.
虔诚  或死亡
Be feared, or be fuel.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
卡伦的母亲
Callan's mother,
在分娩时死亡
died in childbirth.
我多年以来一直责怪他
I blamed him for it, for years.
我不会怪你
I'm not going to blame you.
他还这么年轻
He was so young.
在我的整个生命中
In my entire life,
我从未感到这么的痛苦 我现在要做的
I have never felt so much pain as I do now.
古尔丹不想在霜狼氏族上浪费他的能量
Gul'dan does not want to waste his power on the Frostwolves.
烧死他们
Burn them!
带走弱的  杀掉强壮的！
Take the weak, kill the strong!
我会沐浴在你们的鲜血中
I'll bathe in your blood.
也许 但现在不是时候
Maybe, but not now.
我不能给你太长的时间 但我可以给你一个新的开始
I can't give you long, but I can give you a head start.
为了你们的儿子 德拉卡
For the sake of your son, Draka.
现在……快走
Leave... now.
你本该相信你的酋长 奥格瑞姆·毁灭之锤
You should have trusted in your chieftain, Orgrim Doomhammer.
在这儿等我
Wait for me.
- 卡德加！ - 你怎么敢到这里来！
- Khadgar! - How dare you to come here!
出去！
Get out!
我来寻求你的智慧
I come seeking your wisdom.
这里现在没有什么可以给你的
There is nothing for you here now.
守护者 麦迪文 出问题了
The Guardian, Medivh, is unwell.
什么？
What?
- 他被恶魔能量污染了 - 什么？
- He's been poisoned by the fel. - What?
可笑
Ridiculous.
关于黑暗之门你知道什么？
What do you know of the dark portal?
你回来了 还指责守护者...
You come back, and accused the Guardian...
什么是阿洛迪？
What is Alodi?
他怎么知道？
How does he know?
阿洛迪
Alodi.
这是什么？
What is it?
在肯瑞托出现的时代之前就存在的的实体
An entity from a time before the Kirin Tor existed.
我们认为它起到类似于守护者的作用
We think it serve the functions similar to that of the Guardian.
保护者
Protector.
没有人能够越过议会了解到他的存在 今后也是这样
No one beyond the arch council knows of it's existence, and it will stay that way.
你说黑暗之门的时候同时提到了它
And you to mention it in the same breath
不大可能是...
as the dark portal is too much to be mere...
...巧合
coincidence.
难道我进去？
Do I go in?
不知道 从来没有发生过这种情况
I don't know. It's never done that before.
卡德加
Khadgar.
我知道你  在图书馆的时候
I know you, from the library.
你是阿洛迪？
You're Alodi?
我用我最后的精力 召唤你到这里来
I used the last of my energies to summon you here.
- 守护者已经背叛了我们 - 麦迪文
- The Guardian has betrayed us. - Medivh.
- 我看到了他眼中的恶魔能量 - 他被它所侵蚀
- I saw the fel in his eyes. - He is consumed by it.
如果他没有被阻止  这个世界将会被燃烧
If he is not stopped, this world will burn.
我没有对抗守护者的能量
I don't have the power to defeat a Guardian.
守护者只是一个名字
Guardian is but a name.
这个世界 真正的守护者是人们本身
The true Guardians of this world are the people themselves.
我知道你看到了什么 肯瑞托看不到
I know you see what the Kirin Tor can not.
这就是为什么你离开了他们
It's why you left them.
没有人能独自抵挡……黑暗
No one can stand against the darkness... alone.
我不明白你要我做什么
I don't understand what you want me to do.
不 你明白的
Yes, you do.
相信你的朋友
Trust in your friends.
团结一致 你可以拯救这个世界
Together, you can save this world.
一定要记住...
Always remember.
光明源于黑暗
From light comes darkness,
黑暗涌现光明
and from darkness... light.
起来 起来
Up, up.
谢谢你 摩洛斯
Thank you, Moroes.
你将会复苏的 监护人
You'll recover, Guardian.
你总能做到的
You always do.
不...... 谢谢
No... Thank you.
为你所做的一切
For everything you've done.
对不起 老朋友
Sorry, old friend.
看来我已经让兽人来到这个世界
It seems I have let the orcs into this world.
恶魔能量已经扭曲了我 我...
The fel has twisted me. I...
...甚至不知道 我还可以做什么
don't even know what else I may have done.
我只是记不清了
I just don't remember.
我拼命保护的 我已经……被摧毁了
Everything I fought to protect, I have... destroyed.
我无法控制恶魔能量
I can't control the fel.
没有人能
No one can.
五个军团封锁逆风小径
Five legions to block Deadwind Pass.
这里另外十个 在这里 还有这里  沿着赤脊山脉
Another ten here, here, and here, along Redridge Mountains.
补给线在这里
Supply lines here.
同时在东部海岸的从南部和东部包围他们
While the Eastern Sea hems them in both south and east.
如果我们保住这些据点 我们就会保证最有力的状态
If we hold these positions, we will be at our strongest.
只是遏制？
Containment?
直到有一个更好的选择 是吗？
Until there is a better option, yes.
到时候就是十倍之多了
And where there is 10 times as many.
然后呢？
What then?
如果有简单的答案...
If there were easy answers...
我们必须优先阻止传送门打开
Our priority must be to stop the gate from opening.
如果那里失败了 那在他们以绝对数量击败我们之前
Fail there, and it's just a matter of time
只是一个时间问题了
before they beat us with sheer numbers.
你有什么建议？
What do you suggest?
出动我们的一切
Send everything we got.
摧毁传送门 解救我们的人民   直接结束威胁
Destroy the gate, free our people, and end the immediate threat.
- 剩下的兽人呢？ - 我们之后再来对付他们
- And the Orcs that remain? - We'll take care of them later.
在他们已经破坏了整个王国之后？
After they've ravaged the entire kingdom?
- 陛下 - 麦迪文你好起来了
- My Lords. - Medivh. You are up and well.
是的 我觉得...已经恢复好了
I am. I feel... restored.
我们需要你 我们一直苦苦思索我们的选择
We need you. We've been agonizing over our options.
有些人认为 已经没有选择了
Some of us believe there are no options.
- 我们需要新的思路 - 我有些新的消息
- We need fresh eyes. - I have news.
- 我曾与杜隆坦会面 - 你见了杜隆坦
- I've met with Durotan. - You met with Durotan.
反对古尔丹的叛乱正在发展壮大
The rebellion against Gul'dan is gaining strength.
有了他们的帮助 我们可以摧毁这个门
With their help we can destroy this gate.
- 这并没有改变我的计划 - 什么计划？
- That doesn't change my plan. - What plan?
安度因认为 我们应当全力进攻
Anduin believes we should attack with full force.
而我担心它会使王国其他地方手无寸铁
I'm concerned it leaves the rest of the kingdom defenseless.
需要多少军团在地方阻击兽人？
How many legions would you need to hold the orcs in place?
五个在逆风小径 十个在赤脊山
Five for Deadwind Pass. Ten for the Redridge Mountains.
还要超过十个保证城市的安全
Ten more to protect the city.
那我们已经少了18个军团
We've already lost 18 legions.
- 那留下一个 两个 三个 - 还能办到吗 麦迪文？
- That leaves one, two, three. - Can it be done, Medivh?
不 明显办不到
No, it can't be done.
只需要三个军团 霜狼氏族 还有我的力量...
With three legion, Frostwolves, and my power...
恕我直言 守护者 你的力量
With all due respect, Guardian, your powers
已经证明不可靠 尤其是最近
have proven unreliable at best recently.
- 莱恩我曾经让你失望过吗？ - 让他失望？
- Llane. Have I ever let you down? - Let him down?
你这六年去了哪里？
Where have you even been for the last 6 years?
请不要这样 安度因 麦迪文是守护者...
Please, Anduin. Medivh is the Guardian...
他已经不是那个你记忆中的人了
Not the one you remember.
他失手了 他是不稳定的
He's lost it. He's unstable.
当你真的需要他的时候他不会在那儿的
And he won't be there when you really need him.
找准你的位置 安度因
Find your bearings, Anduin.
如果我觉得有半点机会的胜利
I'd march into hell for you,
我会为你进军地狱的
if I thought there was a slightest chance of victory.
但现在还没有  这简直是自杀
But there isn't, this is suicide.
是因为卡伦？
Is this about Callan?
这是一个悲剧
It was a tragedy.
如果他没有努力尝试来赢得你的认可
If he hadn't been trying so hard to win your approval,
- 他可能仍然和我们在一起 - 麦迪文
- he might still be with us. - Medivh.
卡伦还没有准备好 你知道这一点
Callan wasn't ready. You knew it.
- 你让却无论如何让他做了一名战士 - 安度因 停下！
- And you let him play soldier anyway. - Anduin, stop!
你害死了他！
You killed him!
指挥官 不要这样 长官不要这样
Commander. Please, sir. Please.
瓦里斯 带他去禁闭室冷静一下
Varis. Take him to a cell to calm down.
你现在这样对我们没有什么帮助
You are no use to us like this.
我们会保护王国的 陛下
We'll protect the kingdom, my lord.
你和我
You and I.
你为什么在这里？
Why are you here?
国王叫我来的
The king.
他去对抗部落
He goes to fight the Horde.
有了你们的守护者的帮助  杜隆坦会杀了古尔丹
With your Guardian's help, Durotan will kill Gul'dan.
不要相信他
Don't trust him.
我告诉过你  兽人不撒谎
I've told you, Orcs do not lie.
不是杜隆坦
Not Durotan.
不要相信麦迪文
Don't trust Medivh.
我会尽量保护你的国王
I will try to protect your king.
不要跟他们去
Don't go with them.
为什么呢？
Why?
我不想你受伤
I don't want you to get hurt.
活着回来
Come back alive.
嘿 霜狼
Hey, Frostwolf.
谁在那...
Who goes...
现在你在哪边都是敌人了
Now you are enemies with all sides.
我会告诉他们这是你干的
I'll tell them it was you.
发生了什么？
What happened?
我很抱歉 杜隆坦
I'm sorry, Durotan.
我没有明白我们如何能够与人类一起
... I did not see how we could side with the humans...
对抗我们自己的同类
against our own kind.
我错了
I was wrong.
古尔丹的恶魔魔法正在摧毁我们
Gul'dan's fel magic is destroying us.
德拉卡在哪里？ 安全的
Where's Draka? Safe?
但其他人
But, the rest...
他们不会追随他的
They won't follow him,
如果他们看到他变成了什么
if they could see what he has become.
我会告诉给他们看的
And I will show them.
没有其他男人可以托付我的家人的安全了  瓦里安
There is no other man I would entrust the safety of my family to, Varian.
在我离开的时间里 保证他们的安全
Keep them safe while I'm gone.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
如果洛萨和我们一起 我会感觉更好
I would feel better if Lothar were riding with us.
我们会没事的
We'll be fine.
我将回到卡拉赞  准备战斗
I'll return to Karazhan and get ready for battle.
在传送门找到我
Find me at the portal.
哇 哇 哇 哇
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa, whoa!
卫兵
Guard.
我知道你只是在做自己的工作  而且做得很好
I know you're just doing your job, and a good one at that.
但我现在已经冷静下来
But I've cool down now.
所以 如果你现在过来打开门
So, if you just come and open this gate.
这样我就可以保护国王去了
So I can protect the king.
打开门！
OPEN THE GATE!
我只是听从...
I am just following my...
- 你到底跑哪儿去了？ - 肯瑞托
- Where the hell have you been? - The Kirin Tor.
它仅适用于头脑简单的 持续大约一分钟
It only works on the simple minded, last about a minute.
你的盔甲 指挥官
Your armor, commander.
对不起了
Sorry.
他们已经出发一整天了
They have a full day ahead of us.
- 我只希望我们不是太晚 - 我们不能跟着他们去
- I just hope we're not too late. - We can't go after them.
如果你不希望拯救艾泽拉斯
Not if you want to save Azeroth.
- 我的国王需要我 - 艾泽拉斯更需要你！
- My king needs me. - AZEROTH needs you more!
如果你想保护国王  我们需要先阻止麦迪文
If you want to save your king, we need to stop Medivh first.
麦迪文在哪儿？
Where is Medivh?
我们得杀死一个恶魔
We got a demon to kill.
去 搜索这边
Go. Search over here.
记住
Remember.
你是杜隆坦和德拉卡的儿子
You are the son of Durotan and Draka,
有着酋长的血脉
an unbroken line of chieftains.
我是杜隆坦 加拉德之子
I am Durotan, son of Garad.
霜狼氏族的酋长
Chieftain of the Frostwolf clan.
我在这里 要杀古尔丹
And I am here to kill Gul'dan.
小鬼不能提出Mak'gora （荣誉决斗）
Ghost cannot invoke Mak'gora. (Duel of honor)
你是没有族人的酋长
You are the chieftain of no clan.
你的族人都成蠕虫的食物了
Your people are food for worms.
我们仍有人在 酋长
Some of us still live, warchief.
需要我快速解决他们吗？
Do I make a quick end of them?
我一直以为你是一个传统的人 黑手
I always thought you were one for tradition, Blackhand.
杜隆坦
Durotan.
你的族人软弱  而你还是一个叛徒
Your clan was weak, and you are a traitor.
如果只是私人的 我接受你的挑战
I accept your challenge, if only to personally
我将撕开你可怜的身体 取出你的心脏
ripped the heart out of your pathetic body.
传送门怎么办？
What of the portal?
咒文开始时你必须准备好
You must be ready when the incantation begins
这不会需要很长时间
This won't take long.
杀了他 古尔丹！
Crush him, Gul'dan!
这是通往兽人家乡世界的咒语
It's the incantation to the Orc home world.
他正在打开传送门  我们需要让他闭嘴
He's opening the portal, we need to shut him up.
咒文
The incantation.
我没有时间陪他玩了 黑手！
I have no time for this. Blackhand!
（...兽人传统...）
(... Orc tradition...)
这是一个Mak'gora （荣誉决斗）
This is a Mak'gora. (Duel of honor)
你要尊重我们的传统
You will respect our tradition.
继续战斗
Keep fighting.
古尔丹作弊
Gul'dan cheats.
- 作弊！ - 你太无耻了！
- Cheating! - Shame on you!
你作弊 古尔丹！
You cheat, Gul'dan!
这不是我们的方式
This is not our way.
叛徒！
Traitor!
古尔丹！
GUL'DAN!
你失去荣誉了
You have no honor.
你们会追随这个...恶魔吗？
You will follow this... thing?
你愿意吗？
Do you?
您将追随这个恶魔？
You will follow this demon?
我不会
I will not.
我追随真正的兽人
I follow a true Orc.
真正的酋长
A chieftain.
愿你的蛋蛋腐烂 恶魔
May your balls rot, demon.
还有谁？
Anyone else?
还有你 酋长
And you, warchief.
你将使用邪能
You will take the fel,
你会变得更强 比任何兽人以往任何时候都强大
and you will become stronger than any Orc has ever been.
而当恶魔能量重塑你之后  你会粉碎小个子们
And when the fel has remade you, you will crush the smallteeth.
现在是我的新的世界
Now claim my new world.
军团！ 停止！
Legion! Halt!
霜狼氏族
Frostwolves.
我们只能靠自己了
We are on our own now.
还有你们
With you then.
救下俘虏
Get to the prisoners.
我们将释放我们的人民！
We will free our people!
冲啊！
Charge!
攻击！
Attack!
快想办法？
Ideas?
真是令人印象深刻 现在试下将他击败吧
Very impressive. Now try shutting him up.
哦 真的是很顺利
Oh, that went well.
Ohhhhh
Ohhhhh.
- 他正在动 快做点什么 - （什么？）
- He's moving, do something. - (What?)
好吧 我来处理这个问题
Fine, I'll handle this.
你把麦迪文管好
You take care of Medivh.
嘿 在这里 大笨蛋傀儡
Hey, over here. Clayface.
趁现在！
Now, men!
开火！
Fire!
来吧 我的兽人们
Come, my orcs.
让恶魔能量释放兽人的能量吧
Let the fel unleash the full power of the Horde.
- 为了古尔丹！ - 为了部落！
- For Gul'dan! - For the Horde!
喂 小子！ 醒来！
Hey, kid! Wake up!
你还好吗？
You alright?
脑子还清楚
Quick thinking.
- 切开它就把它阻止了？ - 是啊
- Slicing it's head off like that. - Yeah.
跟我计划的一样
Just how I planned it.
现在怎么办？
What now?
守护者必须亲自念咒语
The Guardian has to speak the incantation himself.
所以呃... 只要他一直这样做...
So uh... As long as he is doing that...
...我们可以靠近他 分散他的注意力
we can get in close. Distract him.
然后呢？
Then what?
把麦迪文推到（法力）泉水里去
Get Medivh in the font.
就这样？
Is that all?
麦迪文
Medivh.
如果你脑子里还有些意识 老朋友
If there is something of you still in there, old friend,
那就快醒醒
come back to us.
麦迪文
Medivh.
来吧
Come.
杀了我
Kill me.
反正我现在也没有什么活着的理由了
I have got nothing left to live for now anyway.
毕竟 生命就是你需要的燃料 不是吗？
After all, life is just fuel to you, isn't it?
但莱恩 他相信你
But Llane, he believed in you.
不要杀你的国王
Don't kill your king.
不要杀你的朋友
Don't kill your friend.
不管你打算做什么 孩子
Whatever you plan to do, kid.
现在就做
Do it now.
现在
Now.
现在！ 现在！
Now! Now!
现在 孩子！
Now, kid!
快看传送门 它关闭了！
The portal. It's closing!
不
No.
你比他更强大
You're stronger than he is.
光明源于黑暗
From light comes darkness...
黑暗涌现……光明
and from darkness... light.
让我看看你的眼睛
Show me your eyes.
我得走了
I have to go.
我为你感到骄傲
I'm proud of you.
暴风城
Stormwind.
陛下 通过传送门 那是暴风城！
My lord. Through the portal, Stormwind!
谢谢你 守护者
Thank you, Guardian.
瓦里斯！
Varis!
军团 前进！
Legion, forward!
攻击！
Attack!
迦罗娜 跟我一起
Garona, ride with me.
瓦里斯 安排人在外围
Varis, set the men in a perimeter.
迦罗娜 卡罗斯 抽出可用的人手释放囚犯
Garona, Karos, take what men we can spare and free the prisoners.
并通过传送门送到暴风城
And send them through to Stormwind.
形成防线  盾墙！
Form a line, shield to shield!
我们要尽可能的坚持
We will hold as long as we can.
去传送门
Get to the portal.
- 去 - 祝福你
- Go. - Bless you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我需要更多的弹药
I need more powder.
到那边去！ 帮我推！
Get over there! Help me push!
加油 孩子们！ 把你吃奶的力用上！
Come on, boys! Put your scorn into it!
在这里！我们去传送门后面攻击他们！
Go around! We'll attack them behind the portal!
照顾好它
Take care of him.
我们应该离开了
We should leave.
我们要尽力救更多的人
We save as many of our people as we can.
孤独使我们弱
It's the loneliness that makes us weak.
卡德加
Khadgar.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我想拯救我们所有人
I wanted to save us all.
我一直在这样做
I always did.
快走！
Move!
我们已经失去了守护者
We've lost the Guardian.
保护侧翼！ 保护侧翼！
Protect the flank! Protect the flank!
黑手想过来杀了你获得荣誉
Blackhand comes to claim the honor of killing you.
迦罗娜
Garona.
我们俩都死了没什么好处
No good will come from us both died.
看看你的周围 我们已经被包围了
Look around you, we are surrounded.
你杀了我是我们拥有和平的唯一希望
Your killing me is the only hope we have for peace.
你告诉塔利亚说杀了她会带来荣誉
You told Lady Taria that killing her would bring you honor.
那么 杀了我会让你成为英雄
Well. Killing me would make you a hero.
活着
Survive.
为人类和兽人之间带来和平
Bring peace between orcs and humans.
你必须这样
You must.
不！不！
No. No!
她杀了他们的头目  古尔丹
She has killed their chieftain, Gul'dan.
部落的怀抱为你敞开
The Horde embraces you.
兽人
Orc.
Mak'gora. (Duel of honor)
For my son.
杀了他
Kill him.
杀了他！
Kill him!
古尔丹 Mak'gora是神圣的
Gul'dan, the Mak'gora is sacred.
这个人类赢了 完胜
The human won, fairly.
让你的战士履行自己的传统
Let your warriors honor their tradition.
我不会违抗
I will not be disobeyed.
你们还在等什么呢？
What are you waiting for?
照我说的做！
Do as I say!
叛徒！
Traitors!
滚开 别挡路 我会自己来
Get out of my way, I'll do it myself.
谁会服从你？
Who will obey you?
如果你和你的同类上战场
If you go to war with your own kind.
如果你这样做  你将失去的部落
If you do this, you will lose the Horde.
而这场战争才刚刚开始
And this war is only beginning.
给你的儿子
For your son.
你的精神可以教他
So your spirit can teach him.
迦罗娜的匕首
Garona's dagger.
我从莱恩的脖子上拔下来的
I pulled that from Llane's neck.
好吧 必须有一个解释
Well. There has to be an explanation.
是的 她做了她的选择
Yes. She made her choice.
我不相信
I don't believe that.
也许你和我都不像我们想的那样足够了解她
Maybe you and I didn't know her as well as we thought we did.
没有一个城市可以有更大的荣幸了
There is no greater blessing a city can have
一个国王愿意为他的子民牺牲
than a king who would sacrifice himself for his people.
但这样的牺牲必须赢得尊重
But such a sacrifice must be earned.
我们必须值得这样的牺牲
We must deserve it.
如果我们只是坐在一起悼念一个好男人的死亡
If we only show our unity to mourn a good man's death.
难道是莱恩国王错信你们了吗？
Was King Llane wrong to believe in you?
- 不！ - 不！
- No! - No!
我们会为你报仇的 我的女士！
We will avenge you, my lady!
带领我们对抗兽人 洛萨！
Lead us against the orcs, Lothar!
- 洛萨！ - 洛萨！
- Lothar! - Lothar!
为了艾泽拉斯！ 为了艾泽拉斯和联盟！
For Azeroth! For Azeroth and the Alliance!
- 艾泽拉斯！ - 艾泽拉斯！
- For Azeroth! - For Azeroth!
- 为了联盟！ - 为了联盟！
- For the Alliance! - For the Alliance!
魔兽争霸
你将远行 我的小古伊尔
You will travel far, my little Go'el.
我的世界也许失去了  但现在这是你的世界
My world maybe lost, but this is your world now.
从它那儿索取
Take what you need from it.
为兽人建一个家 不要让任何人阻挡你的道路
Make a home for the orcs and let no one stand in your way.
我的领主 您应该明白
My lord. You should see this.
你是杜隆坦和德拉卡的儿子
You are the son of Durotan and Draka,
有着酋长的血脉
an unbroken line of chieftains.
我们的人民现在需要 一个领导者...
And our people need a leader now...
...比以往任何时候
more than ever.